all right so good morning everyone Paul
大家早上好，保罗
and Amelia co-facilitating your skull
和Amelia共同促进您的头骨
today thanks to everyone for joining us
今天感谢大家加入我们
for the Jakarta community hangout or
参加雅加达社区视频群聊或
what do you call it updates expectations
你怎么称呼它更新期望
Paul do you want to say the expectations
保罗你想说期望吗
for the 1-hour call sure you know we've
对于1小时的通话，请确保您知道我们已经
we've been having these calls every
我们一直都在打这些电话
month it's a chance for us to get
一个月，这是我们获得机会
together in the working group and those
在工作组中一起
interested in Jakarta EE to find out
对Jakarta EE感兴趣的人
what's happening to talk about any
谈论什么发生了什么
issues that are out there and it just
问题在那里，它只是
generally make sure that information is
通常要确保信息是
being shared we do it in a variety of
被共享，我们通过各种方式
formats both through the new newsletter
通过新的新闻通讯格式化
that we just put out by the mailing list
我们刚刚在邮件列表中列出的
and so on
等等
but I think just having a chance to
但我认为只是有机会
actually speak have some of the folks
实际说有一些人
who are leading some of the activities
谁领导一些活动
talk is useful but more important to get
谈话很有用，但更重要
questions so so the agenda hopefully you
问题，所以议程希望你
can see my screen that we put together
可以看到我们放在一起的屏幕
is is is fairly packed in terms of
是相当包装
topics we know that there's a couple of
我们知道的主题有几个
key things that are going on as we work
我们工作中正在进行的关键事情
towards Jakarta ee8 and so we'll let
对雅加达ee8，所以我们让
each of the speakers get to those topics
每个演讲者都涉及这些主题
and then we'll open the floor up for
然后我们打开地板
questions at the end of each of those
每个问题末尾的问题
topics the first one is going to be Mike
主题第一个是迈克
Milankovitch who is going to talk about
米兰科维奇将要谈论的
just general updates and then
只是一般更新，然后
essentially both the blog that he put
本质上来说，他所写的博客
out last Friday and and Mike is actually
上周五出去，而迈克实际上是
on a short leash in terms of time so
在短时间的皮带上，
we'll let him go and then you can ask
我们让他走，然后你可以问
whatever questions you have for him and
你有什么问题要问他，
then he's going to have to slip away
那他就必须溜走
so with that Mike are you online and
有了Mike，您就可以上网了，
ready to roll well what anything earlier
准备好早点滚动
minutes in oh sorry I was having trouble
分钟，对不起，我遇到了麻烦
getting off of you yes I'm here and
下车，是的，我在这里，
ready to go can you share your slides or
准备好可以分享幻灯片了吗？
do you want me to deal with it let's
你要我处理吗
have you sure cuz I didn't actually
你确定我实际上没有
click the link alright I'll do the next
单击链接，好吧，下一个
slide please routine so and as Paul said
像保罗说的那样请例行幻灯片
I apologize in advance I can stay for
我提前道歉，我可以留下来
about 30 minutes and then I'll have to
大约30分钟，然后我将不得不
head over to do a repeat of this talk
头去重复这个话题
on the floor red hat summit in the
在地板上的红色帽子首脑会议上
community central so highlights the
社区中心，因此突出了
progress so far so code has contributed
到目前为止的进展，所以代码已经做出了贡献
the TCK is open sourced GlassFish 5.1 is
TCK是开源的GlassFish 5.1，
Java EE 8 certified and is released from
Java EE 8认证并从以下版本发布
eclipse and so it's gone through its its
蚀，所以它经历了它的
first release review through the Eclipse
通过Eclipse进行首次发布审查
development process we at the Eclipse
Eclipse的开发过程
Foundation in conjunction with the
基金会与
jacquard EE working group of created the
提花EE工作组创建了
Eclipse Foundation spec process and from
Eclipse Foundation规范过程以及
that created the the jacquard EEE spec
创建了提花EEE规范
process can't I you know and over
过程我不知道吗？
emphasize how much work it was to create
强调要创造多少工作
an entirely new community-based
一个全新的基于社区的
specification process process from from
规范处理过程从
scratch and that's actually a pretty
从头开始，实际上是一个漂亮的
major accomplishment in its own right
重大成就本身
and stay tuned for tomorrow because
敬请期待明天，因为
we're gonna be publishing our 2019
我们将发布我们的2019年
Jakarta EE developer survey and there's
Jakarta EE开发人员调查以及
some some interesting results there as
一些有趣的结果在那里
well so next slide ok so there's lots of
好吧，下一张幻灯片好吧，所以有很多
different channels and things going on
不同的渠道和发生的事情
to engage with the community so we have
与社区互动，所以我们有
the the community mailing list so please
社区邮件列表，所以请
participate there if you're not already
如果你还没有参加
subscribed the Jakarta Tech Talks
订阅了雅加达技术讲座
you have this call would be the update
你有这个电话将是更新
call or ard update call every month
每月拨打电话或ard更新电话
there's condensed email updates that
有简明的电子邮件更新
happen every month as well Town Hall's
每月都会发生，市政厅的
playa there's a now a blog aggregator on
Playa上现在有一个博客聚合器
Jakarta EE which is gonna help sort of
Jakarta EE会有所帮助
give you a single single place to go and
给你一个单一的地方去
find out what's going on with Jakarta E
找出雅加达E发生了什么
and then highly encourage folks that are
然后强烈鼓励
interested in sort of some of the deep
对某种深层次的兴趣
technical conversations on the future of
关于未来的技术对话
this platform that are now happening at
这个平台现在正在发生
the Jakarta platform dev mailing list
Jakarta平台开发人员邮件列表
and just so everybody understands the
这样每个人都可以理解
Jakarta platform is the specification
雅加达平台是规范
project that is going to be responsible
将负责的项目
for the definition of the platform
用于平台的定义
specification going forward so this is
规范，所以这是
where these platform level conversations
这些平台级别的对话
will be happening not just now but
不仅会发生，而且会发生
in the future for many years to come
未来很多年
next slide okay so I'm assuming I know
下一张幻灯片好吧，所以我假设我知道
that David Blevins is also talking about
大卫·布莱文斯（David Blevins）也在谈论
this after me so I'm not going to steal
这个在我后面，所以我不会偷
his thunder but and this is the basis of
他的雷声，但这是
a blog post that I put out this morning
我今天早上发布的博客文章
as well on behalf of the jacquard a
以及代表提花的
steering committee so in a nutshell
指导委员会简而言之
Jakarta ee8 is going to be fully
雅加达EE8将会全面发布
compatible with Java EE 8 so it still
与Java EE 8兼容，因此它仍然
will use the Java X namespace and we'll
将使用Java X名称空间，我们将
be using the the TC case that have been
使用的TC案例
open sourced at Eclipse without without
Eclipse开源
any changes so for all intents and
任何更改，以便所有意图和
purposes it's the same as the Java EE
目的与Java EE相同
platform but it will enable multiple
平台，但它将启用多个
compatible implementations rather than
兼容的实现，而不是
having GlassFish as the only reference
以GlassFish作为唯一参考
implementation and it's going to be a
实施，这将是一个
completely new licensing and branding
全新的许可和品牌
regime which is actually quite important
实际上很重要的政权
to the ecosystem because it means that
到生态系统，因为这意味着
companies can now use the Jakarta egee
公司现在可以使用雅加达
sailing ship instead of the coffee cup
帆船代替咖啡杯
and saved themselves in many cases
并在许多情况下拯救了自己
literally millions of dollars in
数以百万计的美元
licensing fees and so this isn't a very
许可费，所以这不是非常
important pivot from the from the point
从重点出发
of view of the ecosystem as well the
生态系统的观点
book the most important point is that it
书中最重要的一点是，它
will not break existing Java EE
不会破坏现有的Java EE
applications so anything that runs on
应用程序，因此任何运行
Java EE 8 will run completely unaltered
Java EE 8将完全不变地运行
on Jakarta 88 next slide so the news
在Jakarta 88的下一张幻灯片上，所以新闻
from my blog post last week is that the
上周在我的博客文章中，
main news is that the Java X namespace
主要新闻是Java X名称空间
is not going to be evolved by the
不会由
Jakarta spec process and we're actually
雅加达规格流程，我们实际上是
gonna have to change the names of the
将不得不更改名称
specifications themselves so what that
自己说明什么
means is that there is four things
就是说有四件事
obviously things cannot stay static
显然，事情不能保持静止
forever so where are changes required
永远，所以需要更改
it's gonna have to happen in a different
它必须发生在不同的地方
namespace most likely the Jakarta
命名空间最有可能是雅加达
namespace and this is but this is the
命名空间，但这是
exact topic that's under conversation
正在讨论的确切主题
the the mailing list that I pointed to
我指向的邮件列表
you earlier for do the kind of platform
您较早时就做了那种平台
so if you want to
所以如果你想
dive in and participate in that
潜入并参与
conversation by all means please do next
一定要谈谈接下来
slide and to repeat ourselves again
滑动并再次重复自己
because every we've seen this show up a
因为我们看到的每一个都显示
few times with some major
几次主修
misunderstandings Jakarta ee8 will not
误会雅加达EE8不会
break existing Java 88 applications so
破坏现有的Java 88应用程序
that is a very important commitment to
这是对
make to the community next slide so
制作下一张幻灯片，以便社区
we've done the first two steps on this
我们已经完成了前两个步骤
on this journey so eclipse GlassFish 5.2
在此旅途中，使GlassFish 5.2黯然失色
it might actually be 5.1 if it works
如果可行的话，实际上可能是5.1
just if it really works unaltered will
即使它确实能正常工作，也会
be shipped using Jakarta a branding and
使用雅加达品牌进行运输
we're currently expecting that to happen
我们目前预计会发生这种情况
in the early fall so on or around so you
在初秋时分左右
know think of September 1st plus or
知道想9月1日加上或
minus is is the date for for that and
减号是该日期，并且
then that is the contents what we decide
那就是我们决定的内容
is the content for Jakarta ee9 is going
是Jakarta ee9的内容
to really determine when it shifts so if
真正确定什么时候移动，所以如果
there's you know if the community sides
你知道社区方面
will really need is massive change then
那么真正需要的是巨大的变化
obviously that's going to take longer so
显然，这需要更长的时间，所以
next slide that's it all right
下一张幻灯片就可以了
so pause here and throw it open for a
所以在这里停下来，把它打开一个
couple of questions before we hand the
在我们处理之前的几个问题
baton over to David okay so Mike first
接棒给大卫好吧，所以迈克先
so then you did let you be they update
所以你就让他们成为他们的更新
in less than five minutes five point
不到五分钟五分
five excellent
五好
everybody perfect now everyone what are
每个人都完美，现在每个人都是
your questions and just please state
您的问题，请说明
your name and then the question for Mike
您的名字，然后是迈克的问题
the he's here for the next 20 minutes
他接下来的20分钟会在这里
whoa
哇
only crickets and the car
只有板球和汽车
what's going on daddy did you enjoy
爸爸怎么了，你喜欢吗
yourself during this whole process it
自己在整个过程中
actually probably shaved about two years
实际上大概刮了两年
off my life span so tonight I thought
失去了生命，所以今晚我想
yeah actually just finished that answer
是的，实际上刚刚完成了回答
a little farther back in the 70s there's
早在70年代
to be a really popular poster you could
成为一个真正受欢迎的海报，你可以
put on your wall as a kid that said
小时候放在你的墙上说
something on the lines of the definition
定义上的东西
of stress is the inability to choke the
压力是无法窒息
living out of somebody who dearly
活在一个亲爱的人身上
deserves it okay so who was going to ask
值得，所以谁会问
a question hi this is Tobias I don't
一个问题，嗨，这是托比亚斯，我不是
know if this is appropriate at this time
知道目前是否合适
but since you spend a lot of the time in
但是由于您花了很多时间
in dealing with with Oracle and their
与Oracle及其员工打交道
lawyers it would be really really
律师，那真的是真的
beneficial for all of the community to
有益于所有社区
learn a bit more what the problems were
多了解一些问题
in that process I know that you agreed
在这个过程中，我知道你同意
not to talk too much about that but
不要过多地谈论这个，但是
there is a lot of speculation going on
有很多猜测
on the people that try to figure out
试图弄清楚的人
what what happened and is there any
发生了什么事，有没有
chance - well highlighted a little bit
机会-突出一点
more sure I mean I there's there's
更确定我的意思是我在那里
limits on what I can say but let me try
我只能说些什么但让我尝试一下
to provide a little bit of color and
提供一点颜色和
hopefully that'll help so and and so the
希望这会有所帮助
first point was actually the fundamental
第一点实际上是根本
problem was actually mentioned in the
问题实际上是在
blog which is that what Oracle agreed to
Oracle同意的博客
was to move Java EE to the Eclipse
是将Java EE移至Eclipse
Foundation while maintaining Java and
在维护Java和
Java SE as a as an Oracle property and
Java SE作为Oracle属性，并且
as it and certainly Java as an Oracle
它，当然还有Java作为Oracle
trademark and so
商标等
where it got really complicated is that
真正复杂的是
it is completely normal and expected
这是完全正常和预期的
that when you are Licensing trademarks
当您许可商标时
the owner of the trademark gets to
商标的所有人
impose quality requirements and so this
提出质量要求，所以这
is completely normal and understandable
是完全正常且可以理解的
and who's not a surprise to us or anyone
谁也不会让我们或任何人感到惊讶
but it was I think more the the were the
但我想更多的是
were the things difficult was that some
困难是什么吗
of the quality requirements that Oracle
Oracle的质量要求
thought were appropriate we thought were
认为合适我们认为
constraining the freedom of action of
限制行动自由
the Eclipse Foundation and its
Eclipse基金会及其
communities in ways that we could not
我们无法做到的方式
accept and some of this has talked about
接受，其中一些已经谈到
in the in the board meeting minutes that
在董事会会议记录中
I pointed to in my blog as well I know
我在博客中也指出
it's a little bit hard to to try to
很难尝试
understand out of there but I think one
了解那里，但我认为一个
example that was included in there was a
包含的示例中有一个
there was a
有一个
a proposed requirement that we would
建议的要求，我们将
forevermore agree that any runtime ever
永远同意，任何运行时
shipped from eclipse would be a licensed
从eclipse运送的将被许可
Java Runtime which if you sort of think
Java Runtime，如果您认为
through that that is exactly synonymous
通过那完全是同义词
was saying a runs fine provided by
在说由运行良好
Oracle or one of Oracle's licensees and
Oracle或Oracle的被许可人之一，并且
when we looked at that from a
当我们从一个
perspective of the Eclipse Foundation as
Eclipse Foundation的视角
a trade association under US law and
根据美国法律的行业协会，以及
from an antitrust perspective agreeing
从反托拉斯的角度同意
that we could only ever ship a runtime
我们只能运送一个运行时
that was based on that was licensed or
基于许可或
created by Oracle was not something that
Oracle创建的不是
we felt that we could agree to so it was
我们觉得我们可以同意，所以
one of those situations where despite
其中一种情况，尽管
good intentions on both sides the there
双方都有良好的意愿
was a problem that was a set of
是一个问题
constraints that was simply unsolvable
根本无法解决的约束
so I think that's probably the the best
所以我认为那可能是最好的
summary I can I can provide it at about
摘要我可以在大约提供
the right level of detail
正确的细节水平
okay thank you for that and I understand
好的，谢谢你，我了解
that set of constraints set forward by
提出的那组约束
by Oracle was not based on any legal
由甲骨文不基于任何法律
constraint strictly but also on some
严格限制，但也有一些限制
additional or yes let's say quality
额外还是可以，假设质量
based decisions which they deem
他们认为的基础决策
necessary right well they weren't
必要的权利，他们不是
necessarily legal constraints in the
必然的法律约束
sense that they were you know
感觉他们是你认识的
automatically applied it would if we had
自动应用它，如果我们有
agreed to the contract that Oracle was
同意Oracle的合同
proposing we would have been constrained
提议我们会受到约束
forever in certain ways and forever is a
永远以某种方式，永远是一个
very long time to long comparable to
很长的时间比很长时间
endless loop yes thanks we have yes for
无尽循环是，谢谢，我们有
the question any other questions for
该问题还有其他问题
Mike was that clear yes one question
迈克很清楚，是的，一个问题
Jung is asking Mike do you think there
荣格问迈克，你觉得在那里吗
will be a mind shift in the future on
未来的想法将会改变
the Oracle site No
Oracle网站号
okay thanks that's clear it's a good
好的，谢谢，这很明显
German answer how about that more
德语回答更多
questions for Mike here and ready to for
给迈克的问题在这里，准备为
you to ask him anything that's the
你问他什么是
legendary thing about this call I think
我认为这个电话有传奇色彩
it's important to mention too that this
同样重要的是要提到
isn't something that was just figured
不是刚刚想出来的东西
out in the last week I mean Mike and
在上周我是说迈克和
others have been working with Oracle for
其他人一直在与Oracle合作
oh you know a year and a half to try to
哦，你知道一年半尝试
iron out these issues and so there's a
解决这些问题，所以有一个
lot of consideration that goes in there
那里有很多考虑
and that can't be captured and Mike's
那无法被捕获，而迈克的
brief summary but it is something we
简短的总结，但这是我们的事情
have been around and around and around
已经到处走走了
about so many times that I can't believe
大约很多次，我简直不敢相信
that Oracle would ever change their mind
甲骨文会改变主意
of the situation
情况
hi Matt I'm here from the London Java
嗨，马特，我来自伦敦爪哇
community that sort of had a question
有问题的社区
around the infrastructure etcetera
围绕基础设施等
around
周围
continuing to pass TCK so Oliver some
继续通过TCK，所以奥利弗（Oliver）
specifications under the jacquard brand
提花品牌规格
is that all happening now on it on
就是现在发生的一切
Eclipse or on shared common
Eclipse或共享公用
infrastructure or are we still rely on
基础设施还是我们仍然依赖
individual win yeah right right now
个人赢了，马上
we're running tcks for GlassFish on
我们正在为GlassFish运行tcks
eclipse infrastructure we haven't yet
蚀我们还没有的基础设施
made any commitments that we will run
做出我们将要运行的任何承诺
all of the tcks for all products on the
所有产品上的所有杂物
Klipsch infrastructure because as you
Klipsch基础架构，因为正如您
can imagine that could get pretty
可以想象会变得漂亮
expensive but it's certainly something
昂贵，但这肯定是东西
that we're considering you know it could
我们正在考虑您知道它可以
be a benefit of membership in to Jakarta
成为雅加达会员的好处
working group for example but so it's
例如工作组，但是
something we're considering but other
我们正在考虑的东西，但其他
than GlassFish at this moment the answer
比GlassFish现在的答案
is no I mean I mean but I would point
不是，我是说我的意思，但我会指出
out that what we have accomplished over
证明我们已经完成了
the last you know six to eight months on
您知道的最后六到八个月
the on the building infrastructure side
在建筑基础设施方面
in terms of being able to build
在能够建造方面
GlassFish and run the tcks has alone
GlassFish和运行技巧
represented an awful lot of work for for
代表了很多工作
quite a few people so it's it's been a
很多人，所以这是一个
big undertaking for sure no it's been
可以肯定的大事
very much appreciative
非常感谢
sorry I'm Martina I mean you certainly
对不起，我是玛蒂娜，我的意思是你
have a good feeling for the level of
对水平有很好的感觉
effort required for this because of all
由于所有原因，为此需要付出的努力
of your work and adopt OpenJDK right so
您的工作并采用OpenJDK是正确的
you understand the kind of effort that
你了解那种努力
they go into this yeah it's it's for
他们进入这个是的，因为
those listening it's it's significant
那些听的很重要
it's something that most private
这是最私密的
companies would spend you know a
公司会花你知道的
nautical sum of money and time and
金钱和时间的航海总和
effort on so yeah
如此努力
but I guess if other vendors for example
但我想如果其他供应商例如
Amazon have their own JDK are they
亚马逊有他们自己的JDK
testing the TC case on the adopt open
在采用开放测试TC案例
JDK infrastructure or do they need their
JDK基础结构还是他们需要他们的
own Werner say your name come on you're
自己的沃纳（Werner）说，你的名字来了
better than this
比这更好
come on repeats so just because of
来重复，只是因为
course some of the tests would also be
当然，一些测试也会
by vendors who want to prove that
由想要证明的供应商
they're compatible and with regards to
它们是兼​​容的，并且关于
open JDK if a vendor has their own KDK
如果供应商拥有自己的KDK，则打开JDK
can they test that on a neutral
他们可以在中立位置上测试吗
infrastructure under the open JDK
开放式JDK下的基础架构
umbrella or do they need their own GIS
伞还是他们需要自己的GIS
service and stuff like that well let's
服务和类似的东西让我们
this is not this ask me anything is not
这不是这个问我什么不是
about open JDK so let's take a pass on
关于开放的JDK，让我们继续
that question that's fair or no do you
这个问题是公平的还是不可以
want a reward or do something else with
想要奖励或做其他事情
the question with such a question that
这样的问题
is not going to be answered and focused
不会得到解答和关注
on what we're talking about hey Mark
关于我们在说什么嘿马克
I guess if if another implementation of
我猜是否如果另一个实现
the spec wants to run it that would
规范想要运行它
probably not be the duty of Eclipse
可能不是Eclipse的职责
Foundation either that's basically what
基础要么就是基本
I wanted to point out that would be
我想指出的是
correct speaking for Mike Mike isn't
为迈克正确讲话迈克不是
that correct yep yep that's correct
是的，是的，是的
thank you sorry got a little noisy in
谢谢，对不起，我有点吵
the background here for a second so I
这里的背景一秒钟，所以我
put my machine on mute hmm so about the
把我的机器放在静音嗯，所以
blobs that we're having let me go in
我们正在让我进去的斑点
here many of you have written blogs and
在这里，许多人都写过博客，
for those of you who did not know or
对于那些谁不知道或
were shocked with the blog updates by
对博客更新感到震惊
condition where and when he is scared
条件，在何时何地感到害怕
what's going on on the level of whoa
在Whoa级别上发生了什么
what is happening as a developer can we
开发人员可以做什么？
go into the impact they emotional and
进入他们情感上的影响
whatever you're working on just let's be
无论您在做什么，只要让我们成为
a little more focused on you are working
多关注您的工作
on something
在某事上
and what happened not thought about the
而发生了什么，却没有想到
technical ramifications because
技术方面的影响是因为
otherwise people don't have enough
否则人们没有足够的
information to respond okay mayor do you
信息回应好吗市长你
want to start for Mike
想开始迈克
well you unless there are no more
好吧，除非没有更多
questions for Mike yeah I'm good with
我对Mike的提问很满意
David proceeding FRA all means hmm and
David进行FRA的全部意思是
remember to everyone Mike is here for
记住所有人，麦克在这里
another nine minutes he's at 30 minutes
他还有30分钟的时间是9分钟
all right
好吧
we cannot hear you you're muted
我们听不到您被静音
there we go I am now not muted okay
那我们去吧，我现在不静音了
so we're having a discussion right now
所以我们现在正在讨论
out in the open in terms of how to do
在公开方面如何做
the migration from the Java X namespace
从Java X名称空间迁移
to the Jakarta namespace and you know
到Jakarta命名空间，您知道
how we do this is completely up to us
我们如何做到这一点完全取决于我们
and you know I guess the important thing
而且你知道我猜很重要
to point out is once we're on the other
要指出的是，一旦我们在另一个
side of any migration what we do from
迁移的任何方面
there on out is more or less free from
那里或多或少都没有
any trade market restrictions or
任何贸易市场限制或
external licensing restrictions so you
外部许可限制，因此您
know obviously we under our own
清楚地知道我们自己
restrictions at that moment but for us
当时的限制，但对我们而言
to decide as a community so the North
决定作为一个社区，所以北方
Star sentence that I would say is what
我要说的明星句子是什么
we're focusing on is we want to maximize
我们专注于我们想要最大化
compatibility with Java create and
与Java create和
Jakarta EP or Pugh conversions without
雅加达EP或Pugh转换，无
stifling innovation so that last point
扼杀创新，使最后一点
is important so basically we want to
很重要，所以基本上我们想
remain as compatible as much as possible
尽可能保持兼容
for as long as possible within the
在尽可能长的时间内
bounds that we shouldn't make it hard to
界限，我们不应该很难
innovate in our space we want people to
在我们的空间中创新，我们希望人们
be able to enter into the Jakarta you
能够进入你的雅加达
were just just a quick highlight of what
只是这些内容的一个快速亮点
I'm gonna cover is what I mean transfer
我要掩盖的是我的意思转移
from the java x to jakarta namespace
从java x到jakarta命名空间
what we're imagining in terms of
我们在想象中
compatibility and then the couple
兼容性，然后这对夫妻
proposals we have going on and by the
我们正在进行的提案
way i can't read any cat so if anybody
我看不懂任何猫的方式
has any questions you're welcome to
有任何问题欢迎您
interrupt me at any time okay so what it
随时打扰我好吗
means to go into the department
进入部门的手段
namespace is that effectively anything
命名空间实际上是任何东西
that we want to modify has to be moved
我们要修改的内容必须移动
from say Java X service to like a
从说Java X服务到
Jakarta namespace of of our queue there
我们队列的Jakarta命名空间
such
这样
as jakarta serve themselves but it's
雅加达为自己服务，但这是
someone that is something that is noisy
吵闹的人
everyone meets themselves except in a
每个人都见面，除了
mute when you are asking questions thank
问问题时保持静音，谢谢
you so just to add to that Emilia all of
你，所以只是添加到艾米利亚
the co-hosts you have the power to mute
共同主持人您可以静音
people's I do not you can mute them I am
人的我不，你可以让他们静音
I don't have the baby soon access I will
我没有婴儿不久就可以进入
do it and then David you left unmuted
做到这一点，然后大卫你保持不变
can you convince David your minute so
你能说服戴维吗
for example bean validation will go from
例如，bean验证将从
Java X validation to Jakarta validation
Java X验证到Jakarta验证
jax-rs would go from job XW SRS to
jax-rs将从工作XW SRS转到
Jakarta WS RS and so on and even CD I
雅加达WS RS等，甚至CD I
would have to move that was one of the
将不得不移动那是其中之一
questions that I had you know CGI is
我知道的问题是CGI
technically not an Oracle spec as it
从技术上讲不是Oracle规范
still affected and the answer is guess
仍然受到影响，答案是猜测
anything in the Java EE or Jakarta EE
Java EE或Jakarta EE中的任何内容
umbrella that is now going to be
现在要的雨伞
developed up the Eclipse Foundation is
Eclipse Foundation开发的是
affected so some things which are not
影响了一些不是
affected there are several Java X
受影响的有几种Java X
packages in JVM and outside Java EE in
JVM和Java EE外部的软件包
Jakarta that are not affected and some
雅加达不受影响，有些
of them are are not the ones you would
他们不是你会的
think so you know for example Java X RMI
想想，例如，您知道Java X RMI
and Java X naming which is J&amp;I they're
Java X命名就是J＆I
not affected jonathan x sequel which is
不受影响的乔纳森x续集是
all of JDBC that's not affected there
在那里不受影响的所有JDBC
are several XML packages like stream
有几种XML包，例如流
transform and XPath all not affected as
转换和XPath均不受影响，因为
well
好
there's JMX types things which are none
有JMX类型的东西都不是
of that is affected so I was one of the
其中的一个受到影响，所以我是其中之一
very first rounds of feedback that we
我们的第一轮反馈
noticed when the tweets
在发推文时注意到
happening is people imagining like all
发生的事是人们像所有人一样
Java X is gone that is not the case and
Java X消失了，事实并非如此，
they were also imagining that you could
他们也在想像你可以
just do a simple one Java X to Jakarta
只需对Jakarta做一个简单的Java X
mapping and you're done it won't be in
映射，您完成后就不会进入
the case in a little more would be more
在多一点的情况下会更多
like 50 60 mappings there won't be
像50 60映射将不会
hundreds but it would be in that
几百个
ballpark okay
棒球场好吗
important topic to clear out when would
清除何时重要的重要话题
repackaging be required okay what would
需要重新包装好吗
cause you to have to repackage something
导致你不得不重新包装一些东西
from Java X into Jakarta if we were to
从Java X到雅加达，如果我们要
add a method to a class that's in the
将方法添加到位于
java api could be as simple as that in a
Java API可能和
parameter to a method overloading a
重载方法的参数
method changing the method changing this
改变方法改变方法
the exception handling any of that type
处理任何类型的异常
of change would require a move from java
的变化需要从Java转移
X into another package like Jakarta and
X放入另一个包，例如Jakarta和
then if we were going to even do
那如果我们要去做
something as small as add an email value
像添加电子邮件值一样小的东西
right say we have we want to add HTTP
正确地说，我们要添加HTTP
patch to surplice okay that requires a
补丁到可以，需要一个
change and then therefore everything's
变化，然后一切都变了
got to get moved from Java X to Jakarta
从Java X迁移到雅加达
changing the behavior of any class so
改变任何班级的行为
we're not changing the method signature
我们没有改变方法签名
but we're fundamentally changing how the
但我们从根本上改变了
implementation works or how the design
实施工作或设计方式
of the of the code should work that
的代码应该可以
requires a move
需要搬家
all right so Java mail is inherently one
好的，所以Java邮件本来就是一个
of those specifications that almost is
这些规格几乎是
entirely you can't separate the
完全不能分开
interface from implementation any change
实现中的接口发生任何变化
in that that requires a repackaging even
甚至需要重新包装
a bug face things that do not require a
一个臭虫面对不需要的东西
repackaging would be just superficial
重新包装只是肤浅的
changes to documentation types of things
事物文档类型的更改
right so if we wanted to update the Java
对，所以如果我们想更新Java
doc that does not require that the code
不需要代码的doc
move from Java X to Jakarta you want to
从Java X移至您想要的雅加达
update the specification document
更新规格文件
to expand some some things make some
扩展一些东西使一些
things clear that does not require a a
事情很清楚，不需要AA
release or migration of Ning spaces they
释放或迁移他们的宁空间
want to update the TCK simply to fill it
想要更新TCK只是为了填充它
out to be more complete assuming we
假设我们更加完整
don't need to change into the api's that
不需要更改为api
does not require a Java ex to Jakarta
不需要Java扩展到Jakarta
transition so important compatibility
过渡如此重要的兼容性
notes so Mike mentioned it already
笔记，所以迈克已经提到了
Jakarta ee8 will not have any namespace
Jakarta ee8将没有任何名称空间
changes at all and will be released
完全改变，将被释放
basically as is all under the Java X
基本上和Java X一样
namespace so there would be no potential
命名空间，所以没有潜力
compatibility concerns in that release
该版本中的兼容性问题
at all Jakarta EE next will be
在接下来的Jakarta EE上，
compatible and that will have to use
兼容，这将不得不使用
some form of of tooling to provide that
提供某种形式的工具以提供
compatibility because it will contain
兼容性，因为它将包含
some form of Java X to Jakarta switch at
某种形式的Java X到Jakarta的切换
least to some level how much is the
至少在某种程度上
discussion we're having now and that's
我们现在正在讨论，那是
open and we'll get to that we've got a
打开，我们会得到一个
stretch that existing applications will
扩展现有的应用程序
run and it won't be you know you've got
运行，这不会是你知道你有
to figure that out for yourself user it
找出适合自己的用户
will be the vendors providing tools that
将是提供工具的供应商
allow those old applications to run so
允许那些旧的应用程序运行
it will be us making sure that these
我们将确保这些
things happen and we'll be accountable
事情发生了，我们将负责
for it will likely not be a requirement
因为这可能不是必需的
of the spec because we want to make sure
的规格，因为我们要确保
that someone new can enter the ecosystem
有人可以进入生态系统
and implement just the Jakarta main
并仅实施Jakarta Main
space or whatever mix of Jakarta and
空间或雅加达和
Java X is there we don't want to deter
我们不想阻止Java X
new implementations from entering and
进入和执行新的实现
that would having to have them choke
那将不得不让他们cho住
down legacy requirements or backwards
降低传统要求或倒退
compatibility requirements to Java EE
与Java EE的兼容性要求
that would you know raise the bar on
你会知道提高标准
them so kind of informally we've
他们是如此非正式，我们已经
discussed amongst ourselves all the
在彼此之间讨论
existing vendors yeah we're gonna
现有的供应商，我们要
% be providing backs compatibility tools
提供背部兼容工具
new vendors will do that if they want to
新的供应商将这样做
be competitive a few questions I can't
有竞争力我不能回答的几个问题
read the questions so I want to I want I
阅读问题，以便我想要我想要我
need a break and there are many
需要休息，有很多
questions and the charts King can we
问题和图表国王我们可以
take a break okay we give either four
休息一下好吧，我们给四个
was um the there was a fear that having
嗯，有人担心
a toccata eight with the java x
Java X中的toccata八
namespace in the jakarta nine with
雅加达九中的命名空间
jakarta thought star namespace would
雅加达认为明星名称空间会
confuse use wouldn't it be better to
混淆使用不是更好
have a different name for the jakarta
雅加达有别的名字
eight version something which probably
八版大概
doesn't have jakarta in it or whatever
里面没有雅加达
so that people later can have a clear
这样人们以后可以清楚
distinction between jakarta is the thing
雅加达之间的区别是东西
with jakarta x jakarta dot star as
雅加达x雅加达点星作为
packages and it would be a clean rule
包，这将是一个干净的规则
otherwise we have the same name but
否则我们有相同的名字
completely different things
完全不同的东西
yeah i think well i think we should hold
是的，我认为很好，我认为我们应该坚持
that question until we have a chance to
这个问题，直到我们有机会
go through the proposals so people can
通过提案，使人们可以
understand what the goals are and what
了解目标是什么
what is you know and what is on the
你知道什么，什么在
table and what's not on the table but i
表，什么不在桌子上，但我
think that's a good question let's let's
认为这是一个好问题，让我们
go ahead so effectively right now what's
现在这么有效地前进是什么
being issued is two proposals these are
正在发布的是两个提案
not the end of all proposals this is to
并非所有提案的结尾
get the conversation going and so people
进行对话，所以人们
can understand kind of what it is that
可以理解那是什么
are the high-level options that that
是那些高级选项
could be done other options are
可以做其他选择
available the discussion is happening
讨论正在进行中
right now on the jakarta ee platform dev
现在在jakarta ee平台开发人员上
mailing list everybody is welcome to
邮件列表，欢迎大家
join that mailing list we have spent you
加入该邮件列表，我们已经花了您
know eighteen months or more getting to
知道十八个月或更长时间
this point so we do not want to spend
这一点，所以我们不想花
another three months arguing about how
再过三个月，关于如何
to handle the namespace change
处理名称空间更改
we want to get this done quickly so the
我们希望尽快完成此任务，因此
conversation is is set to terminate and
对话设置为终止，
stop and conclude on June 19th at that
在6月19日停止并结束
on June 9th hopefully we have a very
希望在6月9日，
clear community consensus at that point
当时就社群达成明确共识
and we are organizing ourselves to get
并且我们正在组织自己来获得
to that level of consensus if no
如果没有，则达到共识水平
consensus is reached then ultimately it
达成共识，然后最终达成共识
will fall in the hands of the spirit of
将落在精神的手中
the specification committee to just make
规范委员会要做的
a choice but you know we're giving it a
一个选择，但你知道我们正在给它一个
month-long shot on the community to
为期一个月的社区拍摄
handle so there's basically two schools
处理，所以基本上有两所学校
of thought on this type of move one
这种举动的想法
school of thought is Big Bang that we do
我们要做的是大爆炸
everything all at once and the other one
一切都一次，另一个
is incremental so how Big Bang would
是增量的，那么“大爆炸”会如何
work is we would move only once it's a
工作是我们只有在
commitment to not trickle the changes
承诺不滴答变化
out over the course of years that we
多年来，我们
would identify what we want to modify
会确定我们要修改的内容
you know what things we would want the
你知道我们想要什么
ability to modify at any point in the
在任何时候进行修改的能力
future maybe not immediately even but we
未来甚至可能不会马上，但是我们
would move them into the Jakara
会把他们搬进Jakara
namespace if we felt that it was a
命名空间，如果我们认为它是一个
specification we wanted to work on in
我们要研究的规范
the future right now or in the future so
现在或将来的未来
all that stuff would get moved we would
所有这些东西都会被我们感动
do it at once okay and then the the
马上做，然后
thinking on top of that is if we were
最重要的是，如果我们
going to do this it would make sense to
要做到这一点，将是有意义的
release that immediately as Jakarta ee9
立即发布为Jakarta ee9
so that the industry had an opportunity
这样行业就有机会
to absorb the change now most people
现在吸收大多数人的变化
when they hear that they go that's a
当他们听到他们走的时候
very boring release I want new features
非常无聊的发布，我想要新功能
we can have a conversation but we have
我们可以进行对话，但是我们有
to understand that the industry is
了解行业
bigger than application server vendors
比应用服务器供应商更大
and application server users there are
那里的应用服务器用户
monitoring tools there are cloud
监控工具有云
platforms there
那里的平台
IDs there are projects like primefaces
ID有一些项目，例如primefaces
built on top of JMS JFS JSF and all
建立在JMS JFS JSF和所有
those things have to migrate and a lot
这些东西必须迁移，而且很多
of times they have to migrate before you
他们不得不迁移之前
can really absorb a change so that is
真的可以吸收变化，所以
one of the reasons that a push out and
推出的原因之一
immediately release the Jakarta ee9 with
立即发布Jakarta ee9
only a job x2 Jakarta namespace change
只有作业x2 Jakarta名称空间更改
is on the table right jakarta e10 would
在桌子右边，雅加达e10会
then be the first thing with new
然后成为新的第一件事
features or if you wanted to do the Mac
功能或如果您想使用Mac
OS X we can call it Jakarta EDX but you
OS X我们可以称之为Jakarta EDX，但是您
know whatever
知道什么
that's all marketing but that would be
那就是所有的营销，但这将是
the first release to contain new
包含新版本的第一个版本
features there are pros and cons to this
功能有优点和缺点
in the pearls list is all the industry
珍珠清单中的所有产业
gets one shot to do the to do the change
一枪做改变
does not have to keep dealing with this
不必继续处理
over and over again effectively the
一遍又一遍地
investment happens once and once the
投资发生一次
once the dust settles we're done with it
一旦尘埃落定，我们就完成了
the other Pro is that on the other side
另一个优点是在另一边
of this
这个的
we're completely free to do all the
我们完全可以自由地做所有
changes we want and without having to
我们想要的改变而不必
worry about it we are not carrying Java
担心它我们不会携带Java
X forward any longer than we have to
X转发的时间超出了我们的要求
there are cons to this this is the
有缺点，这是
largest upfront cost for all the
所有项目的最大前期成本
industry effectively wet the choke down
行业有效地扼杀了cho节
the main space change in one shot and so
一键更改主要空间，因此
it does raise the bar in some regards
它确实在某些方面提高了标准
for people and that does you know make
为人，那你知道吗
potential migrations of apps maybe a
应用程序的潜在迁移可能是
little more complicated this is more
稍微复杂一点
surface area on the change but basically
表面积的变化，但基本上
those are those are the high-level pros
那是那些高水平的职业
and cons I don't know if anybody else in
和缺点我不知道是否还有其他人
the spec committee or who's been
规范委员会或谁曾
discussing on the list as a new pros or
在列表中讨论新的优点或
cons they want to discuss about Big Bang
他们想讨论大爆炸的缺点
specifically Creek it's again alright
特别是克里克，一切都还好
you know and I'd like to know if the TCK
你知道，我想知道TCK
also would be
也将是
affected would that awfully meat
那可怕的肉会受影响吗
migrated to be asked their ego though
移民被问到他们的自我
the intent is that so that that question
目的是为了那个问题
hasn't been discussed I mean I mean so
没有讨论我的意思是
if the specification moved into Java X
如果规范已移入Java X
obviously the test would be testing
显然测试会测试
against Java X that's not a question
针对Java X没问题
that's a that's a certainty the question
那是一个确定的问题
would be is there going to be some way
将会有某种方式
if a vendor claims it can run the Java X
如果供应商声称可以运行Java X
equivalent are there going to be some
等效的会有一些
way to prove that Y in tests probably
在测试中证明Y的方法
the answer is yes it's it's not an
答案是肯定的，不是
agreed upon topic yet but more than
同意话题，但不止于此
likely it would be some sort of
可能是某种
backwards compatibility test for people
人的向后兼容性测试
to run and that could simply be running
运行，那可能只是在运行
your own TCK unmodified on a question
您自己的TCK在问题上未修改
from Young and David I think the amount
来自Young和David，我认为金额
of work you have to do to migrate to
迁移到的工作量
Jakarta e9 then in the scenario is
雅加达e9然后在方案中是
depending on the tooling which will be
取决于将使用的工具
developed first I think and then it's
我认为首先发展，然后
not that gap you have to take it's not
不是你必须采取的差距
an Big Bang in other aspects effectively
在其他方面大爆炸
the statement you think you're trying to
您认为您要尝试的陈述
make is whether you write the tooling
make是您是否编写工具
and it handles 60 namespaces or 30 the
它处理60个名称空间或30个
tooling has to be a same level of
工具必须具有相同的水平
quality yes yeah more or less so the
质量是的或多或少所以
incremental approach is we move as
渐进的方法是我们前进
needed over time and you know
随着时间的推移需要，你知道
theoretically the least noisy of all
从理论上讲，所有噪音最少
changes right so you know there are good
改变正确，所以你知道有好的
50 or 60 packages we have and
我们有50或60个包裹，
potentially we only move things like
可能我们只会移动诸如
jax-rs CEI bean validation JPA stuff
jax-rs CEI bean验证JPA内容
that we really do clearly know we want
我们确实确实知道我们想要
to modify
修改
and borderline things like Java mail you
和诸如Java之类的边界邮件会发给您
know maybe perhaps connector definitely
确切知道也许是连接器
the old you know jsr 88 in 77 which were
您知道77岁的jsr 88岁
management and deployment they kind of
他们的管理和部署
didn't go anywhere even at lunch and
甚至在午餐时都没去
they've been nothing has happened with
他们什么也没发生
them for 15 years you know that stuff
他们15年，你知道的东西
would clearly stay and then of course if
显然会留下来，当然如果
we did want to say if we did a release
我们确实想说我们是否发布了
of Jakarta 89 and contained say you know
雅加达89的评论，说你知道
Java X mail still but in Jakarta de 10
Java X邮件仍在，但在Jakarta de 10中
we wanted to change java xml it would
我们想更改java xml
become Jakarta mail in Jakarta EB 10 and
在雅加达EB 10中成为雅加达邮件
that would mean you would have to keep
那意味着你必须保持
straight in your head was that one Java
在您脑海中就直达一个Java
X or was that one Jakarta in Jakarta EE
X还是Jakarta EE中的那个Jakarta
11 I can't remember what did we switch
11我不记得我们切换了什么
that one so that would be one of the
那一个将是其中之一
considerations but again the positive of
考虑但又是积极的
this one is we don't have to speculate
这是我们不必推测
on anything that we would want to move
在我们想要移动的任何东西上
we simply move it when it is seeing that
我们只是在看到它时移动它
we want to move it in the list of cons
我们想将它移到缺点列表中
is that the industry effectively would
是该行业有效地
have to absorb a change on potentially
必须吸收潜在的变化
every Jakarta release and it could
雅加达的每个发行版都可以
become a theme oh gosh
成为主题哦，天哪
every time I go to update there's more
每次我更新时，都会有更多
package changes and I gotta I gotta
包的变化，我要
migrate more source code to use the new
迁移更多源代码以使用新的
features and I don't really like them
功能，我不是很喜欢
so that's a potential downside of it
所以这是一个潜在的缺点
so the timelines of these things are
所以这些事情的时间表是
unchanged I want to kind of point that
不变，我想指出一点
out it is very very common for people to
对于人们来说，
try to do kind of horse trading because
尝试做种马交易，因为
say you know a is a constant and nine is
说你知道a是常数，而9是
the next version number they view nine
他们查看的下一个版本号是9
as a date
作为日期
and they want to cram as much as they
他们想尽可能多地补习
possibly can into the number nine as if
可能可以进入九号
that's how things work that's not how
事情就是这样，不是那样
things work so not using version numbers
一切正常，所以不使用版本号
if you if we were to want to do any
如果您要我们做任何事情
release of Jakarta EE that is identical
完全相同的Jakarta EE版本
to Java EE eight you know
到Java EE八点
notwithstanding mark's named name change
尽管商标的名称已更改
right
对
so technically identical in every way
在各方面技术上都一样
that's something we could get done early
这是我们可以尽早完成的事情
fall if we were going to attempt any
如果我们要尝试任何失败
form of namespace change and that was
命名空间更改的形式，那是
all we did that's something that we
我们所做的就是那件事
could probably get done in the late fall
可能在深秋完成
to winter even we're going to do any new
冬天，即使我们要做任何新的
features at all even discussions of to
甚至所有关于
pruning or deprecating or removing api's
修剪或弃用或删除api
then we're talking next year okay so
那我们明年再说吧
this is important to talk about because
这很重要，因为
the level of effort doesn't change based
努力程度不会改变
upon what version number you put on it
你放什么版本号上
so one of the most immediate feedback
因此是最直接的反馈之一
that people got was I want the next
人们得到的是我想要下一个
version to become have new features
版本成为具有新功能
because I've waited too long well that
因为我等了太久了
means that your that you're advocating
表示您所提倡的
we skip doing the two releases we could
我们跳过了两个版本
do in the interim and only do the one
在过渡期间只做一个
released next year it doesn't mean that
明年发布并不意味着
that new feature release comes any
该新功能发布了
sooner
早一点
it just means now there will be no new
这只是意味着现在不会有新的
releases and the industry doesn't have
发布，行业没有
the opportunity to absorb the change
吸收变化的机会
while I work at all of them you leave
当我为所有人工作时，您离开
with new releases so there isn't really
带有新版本，因此实际上并没有
anything we can do to change these
我们可以做的一切来改变这些
timelines if we attempt to make our next
如果我们尝试下一个时间表
Jakarta de release a new feature release
雅加达发布新功能
its next year if we want to do some kind
如果我们想做某种明年
of small changes in the middle we can
中间的一些小变化
get them in but there is no ability to
让他们进入，但没有能力
take next year's new release and move it
采用明年的新版本并将其移动
into looser so I think probably that's a
变得松散，所以我认为可能是
good time to ask questions and the mark
是时候提问和打分了
go ahead with your with your topic
继续您的主题
okay pretty much like your proposal
好吧，很像你的建议
then I want to be clear this yes did
那我想澄清一下
work the discussions of all the steering
进行所有转向的讨论
committee you know Kevin Sutter mark
你知道凯文·萨特马克的委员会
littell our en times you know he was
乱扔垃圾，你知道他是
carrying was that was the guy who
携带的是那个
proposed the Jakarta 89 immediate
提议立即雅加达89
release you know some just tons of
释放你知道一些
people I'm only the messenger and so you
人，我只是信使，所以你
know that you know very big thing to do
知道你知道要做的事很大
all this specification committee what we
所有这些规范委员会，我们
could do in the meantime is to think
同时可以做的是思考
about applications because that
关于应用程序，因为
technically doesn't hurt any binary
从技术上讲不会伤害任何二进制文件
compatibility so we should i perfectly
兼容性，所以我应该完美
agree with your arguments that we
同意您的论点，即我们
shouldn't cram into in new features but
不应该加入新功能，但是
we probably if people have spare time
如果人们有空的话
they can think about what features to
他们可以考虑要使用哪些功能
deprecated or not because we would just
是否弃用，因为我们只是
mark them we would not remove anything
标记他们，我们不会删除任何内容
yet but people kind of have a little bit
但是人们有点
more time upfront to plan for stuff
提前安排更多时间来计划工作
which likely will be removed in let's
这很可能会在我们中删除
say Jakarta in a year 10 or 11 so mark
说雅加达在10年或11年左右
you're talking about cutting that in
你在谈论切入
other words yeah so deprecating is one
换句话说，是的，如此贬低是一个
thing actually moving as a way higher
事情实际上正在向更高的方向发展
bar so I agree with you that you know
酒吧，所以我同意你，你知道
actually moving stuff could happen but
实际发生的事情可能发生，但是
now we're talking about like a release
现在我们正在谈论像发布
next year at least in my opinion so I
至少在我看来，明年
don't know if others have opinions I
不知道别人是否有意见
want to be the only one talking at this
想要成为唯一在这个话题说话的人
at some point we should hear the more on
在某个时候，我们应该听到更多关于
this investigation from anybody
任何人的调查
the application is more achievable but
该应用程序更容易实现，但
ultimately you don't release code your
最终您不会发布代码
lease agreement and getting agreement
租赁协议和取得协议
may be difficult and the the sheer
可能很困难，而且纯粹
agreement of it may push the timeline so
它的同意可能会推动时间表
you know that's one of the topics of of
您知道这是以下主题之一
big bang is do we move it all or do we
大爆炸是我们全部移动还是我们移动
move some if we agree to move all the
如果我们同意将所有
decisions short if we agree we're gonna
如果我们同意，我们将做出简短决定
move some then they're gonna be at least
移动一些然后他们至少会
three different perspectives major
三种不同观点的专业
differences
差异
I can I can hold on a second guys we
我可以抱住第二个人
have 15 minutes to go and we have a many
有15分钟的路程，我们还有很多
interest of the specification committee
规格委员会的利益
here I'm a con man we open the board for
在这里，我是个骗子，我们为
in the four others to ask questions on
在其他四个问题上
what has been presented right now in
现在已经呈现的内容
mark you can continue after if there are
标记是否可以继续
crickets 30 seconds
seconds 30秒
do we have topics after this that we
在那之后我们还有话题吗
need to get no we do not
需要得到没有我们没有
there are only two topics Mike's
迈克只有两个主题
presentation and update and the blog
演示和更新以及博客
entry mark and then the two proposals
进入标记，然后是两个建议
okay okay
好吧好吧
device yeah so when I read Mike's blog
是的，所以当我阅读Mike的博客时
post I failed a lot of anger and I think
发布后，我没有生气，我想
that was some kind of motivator to opt
那是某种选择的动机
for the Big Bang this was first my
对于大爆炸，这首先是我的
preferred option and then I read a
首选选项，然后我阅读了
Richards proposal of a legacy profile
理查兹提出的遗留档案建议
and I I really liked the the perspective
我很喜欢这个观点
of not having to carry the cargo forward
不必将货物向前运送
from all the past we had and now I'm
从过去的所有事情，现在我
trying to figure out what's really the
试图弄清楚到底是什么
difference between that legacy profile
旧版个人资料之间的差异
proposal and the incremental approach
提案和渐进式方法
can can you outline it at our day or
您能在我们今天概述一下吗？
perhaps even richer can outline that
也许更富有的人可以概括出
yeah so this is Richard thanks for the
是的，这是理查德感谢
question the legacy okay so call classic
质疑传统好吗，所以称之为经典
are called legacy but at any rate the
被称为遗产，但无论如何
difference is that it's always
区别在于它总是
maintained as a separate thing whereas
单独维护
when you do the incremental poet you'll
当你做诗人时，你会
be mixing Java X along with Jakarta
将Java X与Jakarta混合在一起
namespaces together and my thing
命名空间和我的东西在一起
you can identify the Java X stuff as the
您可以将Java X内容标识为
as as the legacy profile sort of speak
就像旧版个人资料一样
or classic profile then you can the rest
或经典个人资料，然后就可以休息了
of the platformer can evolve without
平台游戏的发展无需
being polluted by the Java X namespace
被Java X名称空间污染
that's the primary difference there's
那是主要的区别
there's there isn't mixing and matching
没有混合和匹配
necessarily so you're saying at some
一定所以你在说一些
point a vendor could choose to drop the
供应商可以选择放弃
legacy profile and still have a
旧版个人资料，仍然有一个
completely workable Jakarta yeah I mean
完全可行的雅加达是的，我是说
I just sent out another email that kind
我刚发出另一封电子邮件
of all kinds a little bit more but
各种各样的，但是
basically the even if you do a big bang
基本上，即使你大爆炸
with Java x2 the Jakarta dance base that
使用Java x2的雅加达舞蹈基地
BIGBANG becomes a profile like classic
BIGBANG成为经典的个人资料
or legacy that anyone can implement but
或任何人都可以实施的遗产
the actual Jakarta platform is
实际的雅加达平台是
independent of that so it only evolved
与此无关，所以它只会进化
with its own profiles and that sort of
有自己的个人资料，
thing and the Java X namespace or that
事物和Java X命名空间或那个
what we identify as the java ee 8
我们确定为Java EE 8
platform will be its own it will be a
平台将是自己的，它将是一个
separate profile that can optionally be
单独的配置文件，可以选择是
implemented by vendors or ignore the
由供应商实施或忽略
media stop sharing place and you can
媒体停止共享位置，您可以
clarified or someone else can clarify
已澄清或其他人可以澄清
whatever was set by Richard well is
理查德很好地设定的是
there somebody else in the screen share
屏幕上还有其他人分享
um someone you are sharing so no no more
嗯，您正在分享的人，所以不再
sharing we go in to check our teeth now
分享，我们现在去检查牙齿
well right I will just leave this on the
好吧，我会留在
other screens that people can you know
人们可以知道的其他屏幕
there's no need because we aren't very
没有必要，因为我们不是很
vocal on the forum and this is in a
在论坛上发声，这是在
minute
分钟
thank you so it sounds like that so
谢谢，听起来像这样
first of all to be clear on them I
首先要弄清楚他们，我
really prefer to to have a screen share
真的更喜欢共享屏幕
so we can
所以我们可以
flip back and forth between the proposes
在提议之间来回翻转
we if we want did the the Big Bang and
如果我们想做大爆炸，
incremental both could involve migrating
增量都可能涉及迁移
only a subset of Java X to Jakarta so
Java X只是Jakarta的一个子集，所以
they they both have to make a decision
他们俩都必须做出决定
of what to what we're gonna migrate and
我们将要迁移的内容
the difference with Big Bang we're
与大爆炸的区别是
making a commitment commitment to the
对...做出承诺
industry this is the only it'd be done
行业，这是唯一要做的
once and you don't have to worry about
一次，您不必担心
paying this cost all the time and is it
一直在支付这笔费用，是吗
something you can rely on as a user or
您可以作为用户依赖的东西
to developer of tools or anything that
给工具或任何其他东西的开发者
you're not going to be doing this for
你不会为此做的
the next 10 years and so both of them
接下来的十年，所以他们俩
involve potentially a subset being moved
涉及可能移动的子集
obviously with the Big Bang we got to
很明显，我们有了大爆炸
put a lot more thought into what we move
在我们的行动中多加思考
up front and with incremental we don't
预先和增量我们不
it sounds like the concept of although
听起来像
you know call it you know there's a
你知道叫它你知道有一个
stomach at the classic profile whatever
胃口经典
is basically on top of either of those
基本上在这两个之上
everything that's in the Jakara
Jakara中的一切
namespace is the new stuff and
命名空间是新的东西，
everything that's Java X is classic and
Java X的一切都很经典，
so it sounds like that kind of concept
所以听起来像是这样的概念
could apply to either Big Bang or
可以适用于大爆炸或
incremental does that does that match
增量式匹配吗
your understanding Richard yeah I mean I
您的理解Richard是的，我是说我
thought of it both in terms of Big Bang
从大爆炸的角度来思考
the important part is that that classic
重要的是那个经典
profile is frozen it's frozen set aside
个人资料被冻结，它被冻结搁置
vendors can choose to implement it if
供应商可以选择实施
they want to but you don't have to
他们想要，但您不必
implement to be considered Jakarta
实施被认为是雅加达
compliant there the Jakarta platform
符合Jakarta平台
itself will evolve with many other kinds
本身会随着许多其他种类而进化
of profiles that you can combine in a
可以合并到一个配置文件中
classics just what's the difference to
经典与有什么不同
just having in the old application
只是在旧的应用程序中
server running I mean nowadays the days
服务器运行我的意思是如今的日子
of the big islands where you have one
那里有一个大岛
server and dozens applications 100
服务器和数十个应用程序100
certifications running on them they're
在他们身上运行的认证
over usually you have one or two
通常你有一两个
applications running on the same server
在同一服务器上运行的应用程序
if you have another application start up
如果您有另一个应用程序启动
a new server so and those all
一个新的服务器等等
applications couldn't could run on an
应用程序无法在
old profile so I don't see reason why we
旧的个人资料，所以我看不出为什么我们
should have a runtime supplying or
应该有一个运行时供应或
supporting both versions the old ntinue
支持两个版本的旧版本
one you don't have to you can support
一个你不需要的可以支持
one or the other but remember that to be
一个或另一个，但要记住是
a Java EE application server there's
Java EE应用服务器
trademark and marketing requirements
商标和营销要求
associated with that yeah we wouldn't be
与那相关，我们不会
in any way you know nothing that we're
无论如何你都不知道我们
producing would allow someone to ship a
生产将允许某人发货
Java EE application server we don't have
我们没有的Java EE应用服务器
they could ship a Jakarta
他们可以运送雅加达
eight compliant app server which is
八个兼容的应用服务器
effectively the same problems the reason
有效地解决相同问题的原因
why we were discussing this is why
我们为什么要讨论这就是为什么
because we want to provide compatibility
因为我们要提供兼容性
and that means that you have an existing
那意味着你已经有一个
big application that probably is not not
可能不是这样的大应用程序
so easy to migrate in in one big goal so
容易实现一个大目标
you will pick parts of it and and
您将选择其中的一部分，并
migrate it to the new world to the
将其迁移到新世界
Jakarta world and over time you will be
雅加达世界，随着时间的流逝，您将成为
able to then leave the classic profile
然后可以离开经典个人资料
behind so this is how it will be used
在后面，这就是它的用法
and and how it can can be done in a
以及如何可以在一个
company to be clear you don't intend say
公司要明确你不打算说
say you you are a jacquard EEE user and
说您是提花EEE用户，并且
you have an app that already was and
您已经有一个应用了，
Jakarta EE 11 comes out let's let's go
Jakarta EE 11推出，让我们开始吧
let's say Jakarta e9 because that's the
假设Jakarta e9是因为
state when you talk about you want to
陈述您要谈论的内容时
not update your application and run it
不更新您的应用程序并运行它
on the Jakarta e9 server for the
在Jakarta e9服务器上
existing vendors we've all committed to
我们都致力于的现有供应商
making sure that that application will
确保该应用程序将
run without modification so the only
无需修改即可运行，因此唯一
time that you would have to do any work
需要做任何工作的时间
on your side is it you wanted to start
在你这边是你想开始
using a new
使用新的
feature in Jakarta de9 safe there are
雅加达de9安全功能包括
new servlet enhancements or new jax-rs
新的Servlet增强功能或新的jax-rs
enhancements in which case then you
在这种情况下，增强功能
would have to migrate your source code
将不得不迁移您的源代码
from Java X our SWS to Jakarta WS dot RS
从Java X我们的SWS到Jakarta WS dot RS
kind of got the packages a little bit
有点包装
backwards there but more than likely
向后倒退，但可能性更大
there will be plugins in Eclipse
Eclipse中会有插件
IntelliJ and so on so forth
IntelliJ等
that helped you do that source code
帮助您完成了源代码
migration so you can take advantage of
迁移，以便您可以利用
the new features and start coding
新功能并开始编码
against them because we won't be able to
反对他们，因为我们将无法
modify the Java X namespace it also
修改Java X名称空间
Richards key point about the classic
理查兹关于经典的要点
profile that it's frozen it never
配置文件，它永远冻结
changes that's always going to be the
改变永远是
case because we can't legally change
案例，因为我们不能合法改变
Java X so it's not a it's not a proposal
Java X，所以这不是一个提议
it's a constant that part of the
这是恒定的一部分
proposal but anyway so the only time you
建议，但无论如何，只有你
would have to do any work on your side
必须在你这边做任何工作
as a user is when you want to use any
作为用户是当您想使用任何
enhancements that are made to existing
现有的增强
api's because they'll always be under
api是因为它们将始终处于
the java acts namespace and so
java行为名称空间等
realistically say jakarta ee 11 is going
现实地说，雅加达EE 11即将进行
to contain some mix of formerly Java X
包含以前的Java X的一些组合
api's moved in Jakarta and completely
api完全移居雅加达
brand-new Jakarta API like just was a
全新的Jakarta API就像是
imagine a couple years on the future
想象未来的几年
right will be both that will get a mix
正确的将两者混合在一起
of both there may still be some Java X
两者可能仍然会有一些Java X
packages hanging around that are used
周围使用的包裹
but we don't ever intend to modify them
但我们绝不打算修改它们
in which case they're frozen they're not
在这种情况下，他们被冻结，他们没有
prude
粗鲁的
they're not deprecated necessarily
他们不一定被弃用
they're just they're perfect they're
他们只是他们是完美的他们是
fine we don't expect to need to change
很好，我们不需要更改
them at all
他们都
question well actually - I do need the
问题很好-我确实需要
specification committee to tell us
规格委员会告诉我们
aside from the kids how do we continue
除了孩子们，我们如何继续
the conversation
对话
I don't expect another please put it
我不希望其他人放
back up David that would be great yeah
备份大卫那太好了
just just to wrap this up thank you
只是为了总结一下谢谢
everyone for the questions and David
每个人的问题和大卫
thank you very very much for going
非常感谢你的努力
through this it's useful just to kind of
通过这种方式，对于某种
walk through what the choices are so so
逐步了解选择是什么
it's been useful for me and hopefully
对我很有用，希望
others on the call also thanks to Mike I
通话中的其他人也感谢Mike I
know he's had to leave but I appreciate
知道他必须离开，但我很感激
him doing this as well
他也这样做
the conversation continues right on the
对话继续在
mailing list that's the place to jump in
邮件列表是跳进去的地方
and joining as David said it will go
并按照大卫说的去参加
until we're targeting June 9th but if
直到我们将目标定在6月9日，
consensus comes out of this earlier will
这个较早的意愿产生了共识
certainly work towards that yeah the
肯定会朝着那个方向努力
other thing is you know the other topic
另一件事是你知道另一个话题
that we wanted to get to and we just
我们想要去的，我们只是
weren't going to have time today is you
今天不会有时间是你
know the planning and the work that has
知道计划和工作
to go in to get Jakarta ee8 out the door
进入让Jakarta ee8出局
so we you know most of what David has
所以我们您知道戴维拥有的大部分
talked about is assuming that car d8 is
谈论的是假设汽车d8是
done and then where do we go from there
完成，然后我们从那里去
right so we're gonna be calling on all
对，所以我们将呼吁所有
of you who are on this call to engage in
参与这项通话的你们当中
helping us get that done and so watch
帮助我们完成任务，因此请注意
for that discussion
为了那个讨论
I think over the next few days and weeks
我认为在接下来的几天和几周内
because you know they as as as was
因为你一如既往地了解他们
talked about either by Mike or David you
谈论过迈克或戴维
know ideally we'll get this out by early
知道理想情况下我们会尽早解决这个问题
fall but that only happens if we roll up
下降，但只有在我们向上滚动时才会发生
our sleeves so in both the
我们的袖子既在
solidification the minutes do have the
凝固分钟确实有
Jakarta e8 repo it's ready so there's no
雅加达e8仓库已经准备好了，所以没有
reason to wait everyone King is not
等每个人的理由国王不是
contributing we have the report 890 and
我们提供了890号报告，
what comes next
接下来是什么
great thank you a million so who's
非常感谢您一百万，那么谁是
beautiful yep so I think that's it thank
是的，是的，我想就是了
you everyone for participating as Amelia
大家作为阿米莉亚参加
noted this is recorded and we'll get
注意这已记录下来，我们将得到
this posted but I think it's been a
发布，但我认为这是一个
useful discussion and and we'll see you
有用的讨论，我们将会见到您
next month we have one minute and one
下个月我们有一分钟零一分钟
question this one I wanted to ask and I
问这个我想问的问题，我
don't want to give that but we can try
不想给，但我们可以尝试
try it be quick before we go go and
快点尝试，然后再去吧，
thanks everyone for joining today guys
谢谢大家今天加入
go okay um hi this is Scott
好的，嗯，这是Scott
Marlowe
马洛
so Java X is considered frozen on the
因此Java X被认为冻结在
jihad aside
撇开圣战
is it frozen from Oracle at least is
是否至少从Oracle冻结了？
that the intention you know the Oracle
你知道甲骨文的意图
will also not be making Java X changes
也不会进行Java X更改
in the coming years or is I really not
在未来几年还是我真的不是
known at this point only to the if at
在这一点上只知道在
all to the Jakarta ee Java X packages
全部交给Jakarta ee Java X软件包
thank you as I mentioned there are a lot
就像我提到的，谢谢你
of unaffected packages obviously those
不受影响的包裹显然是那些
will be updated as they need to the part
将根据需要进行更新
of Java SE thank you
Java SE的谢谢
smallish addendum there are some Java X
小附录有一些Java X
packages which are referencing Java X
引用Java X的软件包
from Jakarta which are the e space like
来自雅加达的e空间就像
Java X SQL and we have to tweak those
Java X SQL，我们必须对其进行调整
little bits
一点点
or at least keep them in compactly all
或至少将它们紧凑地存放
right so we are ending on time thank you
对，所以我们准时结束了，谢谢
so much everyone for joining it was a
所有人都参加了
pleasure to see everyone today and the
很高兴见到大家今天和
questions were great let's continue the
问题很棒，让我们继续
conversation in the forum in its rockets
在论坛上的对话
happy May month bye everyone
祝大家五月快乐再见
hi thank you
嗨，谢谢你